Brooklyn, NY

avshar@pm.me http://avshrk.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a full stack engineer with solid background in computer science fundamentals. I have multiple years of experience building consumer facing software with proficiency in Ruby, Rails, Node, JavaScript, Linux, Unix and RESTful APIs.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

CushionDB Brooklyn, NY

May 2019 – Present

- Built an open source data management framework for offline-first progressive web applications.
- Implemented preemptive data push (server push) to reduce web application latency.
- Reduced DOM blocking by separating long running computation from the main thread.
- Implemented Multi-leader data replication/synchronization architecture among user databases.
- Utilized Service Workers and Push Notifications to implement bidirectional data synchronization between user databases even if the web application is closed.
- Simplified deployment and dependency issues by packaging and deploying Docker images for server side components.
- Reduced HTTP traffic by employing network connectivity events.
- Wrote a comprehensive case study (https://cushiondb.github.io)

Full Stack Developer

Mita Consulting USA Inc.

Brooklyn, NY

September 2015 - May 2019

- Built Ruby/Rails full stack ecommerce web applications for multi channel merchants.
- Built JavaScript/Node microservices such as managing inventory, monitoring competitors, and tracking shipments.
- Integrated web apps with Amazon market place via RESTful APIs.
- Built an extensive number of web applications with Ruby/Rails, Node/JavaScript and React/Redux.

Founder

Partners Modusvivendi Inc.

Brooklyn, NY

June 2008 – January 2013

• Built and operated multi channel ecommerce company with over \$300K annual sales.

PROJECTS

PostIt: A social news and discussion application similar to Reddit built with Rails, PostgreSQL, and JavaScript.

Project Board: List management productivity web app built with Ruby/Rails and React/Redux.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, Ruby, JavaScript, Bash Shell Script, SQL **Back End:** Rails, Node, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MySQL, RESTful APIs

Front End: React, Redux, HTML/CSS, jQuery **Other:** Git, Docker, FreeBSD, Linux, CouchDB

EDUCATION

Louisiana State University – Baton Rouge, LA

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems and Decision Sciences